Really, this is where I started to lose
my innocence. And I'd been out here
drinking them natty daddies and swimming
in the lake and it was hot. I
hear and a big ass Boston wherer comes
pulling up right here. It was the DNR
and we was right here in this very spot.
I went like that. He said, "Don't do it,
boy." I said,
"Boom." I'm drunk as I'm running from
the police and I am 138 pounds of natty
daddy and adrenaline at this point. Joe,
so where did you bring me? This is
Hippie Cove, man. When I think back on
it, dude, like really, this is where I
started to lose my innocence, you know?
I was just a barefooted country boy,
man. I like to run around in the woods
and swim in the lake and drink beer and
catch snakes and shoot guns and fish. I
mean, that's all I wanted to do. And I
was out here right here in this very
spot in uh I think it was June, July of
2005. I was sitting here with my
girlfriend at the time. And I'd been out
here drinking them natty daddies and
swimming in the lake and it was hot. Let
me come over here and hop in the water.
And I come right over here to these
rocks. So I go and I jump in. It's hot.
I cool off. And I was just in a pair of
khaki shorts and I put a towel around me
and I took my shorts off and I rung them
out and I laid them on that rock right
there to dry in the sun. I was sitting
right here with my ass on this rock
drunker and cooter brown mining mine
swimming in the lake. I
hear and a big ass Boston whaler comes
pulling up right here. You know what?
What? I'm just, you know, literally have
no clue what's going on. And I remember
they get over here and they pull up
right there. They get out and the first
thing they say is, "Where's the dope?"
"What do you mean, what dope?" And so,
we ain't got no dope. Nah, where's the
dope? We can smell it. What are you
doing? I said, "What? I'm sitting here.
Are you naked?" "Well, yeah, I mean,
yeah, I just went for a swim. I'm
letting my shorts dry right there. Come
with me." Okay. It was the DNR. The
Federal Law Enforcement Division had
been watching us with binoculars from a
boat way out there. So, what we were
doing would be known as minding your own
business in most parts of the world, but
not in the great state of South
Carolina. So, they're marching us back.
You know, I'm out on three cases right
now. I'm on felony probation from that
in Athens, Clark County. I got
misdemeanor probation from Lincoln
County Times 2. I'm like, man, I'm
fitting to go down for another felony,
man. Come on, dude. And so I'm walking
down this path, man. And I'm just like,
you know what? This these mother on a
boat, dog. If we on dry land and all
they got is a boat, that means it's foot
on foot. Now, I'd run from the cops one
time in my life, but not like this. It
was a party when I was in high school,
right? And uh the cops showed up and I
was in the backyard and siren started
blaring and I took off and I jump one
fence, two fence, three fence, boom,
boom, boom, gone. That wasn't like this.
These had my ID that was behind me and
we was right here in this very spot. I
was wearing a pair of rainbow sandals
and I come over this this route right
here and went shoot. I kicked him off. I
went like that. He said don't do it,
boy. I said you
boom. He just disappeared on me. That's
what they thought, too. I got up here
and I heard his radio. I'm drunk as and
I'm running from the police and I am 138
pounds of natty daddy and adrenaline at
this point. So I come up and I run up
this hill and I come up when I get to
here I look back coming on that bend and
he looks at me he says son don't do it.
I was parked some ways about middle ways
of this and I run up here. What it was
was a white Nissan Ultima that was 2/3
gone. There was no front bumper on it.
There was no side
fender. It had to go. So, I'm going to
show you where we go
next. So, I run up, man, and I get in
this thing and I hit it real fast and I
pop in this guy and dude, I'm gone,
right, man? I'm in this car, dude, and I
realized I'm running from the federal
government. Holy, I'm an 18-year-old kid
and I'm also drunker than Cterbrand.
Yeah, punch it. And he's screaming
behind me. What do I do? So, I punched
out of here and I hung a left and my
heart is pounding and I realized, holy,
I just ran from the cops. I don't know
what happened to her. I don't know if
they got my license plate. I don't know
where I'm going. Oh my god. Oh my god.
My head starts to spin. This can't be
happening. This can't be happening. Get
off the road. I had a donut on the front
right. I was in no shape to be running
from the law. And out of fear, I
literally just took the first turn out
of there. And I'm hauling at hauling ass
down this thing fast as I don't know
what I'm thinking. A combination of
natty daddy and adrenaline had me
spinning, bro. And all I was doing was
minding my own business, man. I was
literally doing nothing but sitting on
the bank minding mine, swimming in the
lake. What did I do to anyone? I'm just
wanting to get away. That's all I wanted
my whole life was just to be left alone
is just leave me alone. I drove all the
way the out here just to be left alone
and can't even do that. And I pulled
down him. I mean, this was 17, 18 years
ago, you know. I mean, it looks
different now. Might have been it. Yeah.
There was a little dip. I couldn't go no
further. There it is. Shut my car off
and passed out. Mhm. The adrenaline dump
everything. And I don't know how long I
was out or what. I have no clue. Laid
back like that. And I heard I heard a
bunch of noise of
commotion noise. And I heard dog all
kind of sh and I and I come up. I look
in my rearview mirror. I see cop lights
and I hear dog. So what do I do? I Hey.
And I'm gone. I'm gone.
Hey. Gone. You ain't going to get me,
dog. Like I don't need a trail. I don't
need I don't even need a head start. And
I take off on a right and I'm running
and I hear him on a bullhorn. Stop where
you are. Get down on the ground. Nah.
That fat boy won't catch me. Going to
have to beat your feet. Stop where you
are. Get down on the ground. Nah, I'm
running. Then they say, "Stop where you
are or we're going to release the dog."
Oh boy. I can't outrun no dog right now.
I'm walking backward to the sound of
your voice. And so they get me down
there, put me down like this, and
handcuff me. And they and I'm down my
belly like this giving them hell. Y'all
stupid mother could catch me without a
[__] dog, man. K9 unit. You know what
that means? ninth grade, farther than
any y'all has ever made it. I mean, I
was giving them hell. And so they picked
me up, one on each arm, and two of them
had my legs and they carried me like
this. And I was giving them I said, "You
so dumb. Y'all milk and cookies have
pickles and goddamn soda." I just
remember the one that I told them that
really set them off. I said, "That's why
somebody's at home hitting your old lady
right now." Hey man, they didn't say a
word. Them took and threw me face first,
shirtless, into a pile of poison ivy.
Hey, you know what? I get down
there today. I'm immune to that. I've
been in that so long living in the
country. Y'all can't do nothing right.
Hey, guess what? They didn't say a word.
They scooped me right on up. They was
walking me out here. Hey, I was cussing
them, giving them hell. You know what
they did? They stopped off. Hey, they
threw me face first in a brier patch.
God, take all the fight at you, son. You
ever laid face down naked in a pair of
brier patches? Can't say I have. God,
dude. I uh I don't know how long I was
there but after a while uh um excuse me
sir you know I've been down here for a
little while could you please get me off
these briers cuz man it hurt you trying
to lean away from one side and he dig in
there so you trying just had to lay
there and take it bro I mean I was
probably there 20 minutes oh you ain't
got nothing else to say smartass you
immune to prior too no sir no sir
evidently not then I was on my way to
McCormack County Jail where they booked
me in on felony possession with intent
to distribute yeah I was going to sell
that that's why I was out smoking it on
the banks of the lake. Uh it's my
understanding that they had a boat, but
they also had a helicopter. I didn't I
didn't know that little that little
detail. And I'm going to take you to one
more spot. All right. And I've run from
the law five times. I've only been
caught twice. I was caught right there.
And the other time was when I went to
prison, obviously. And I'm going to take
you to a place where they ain't catch
me. All right. In the van.
Why the are we out here in the middle of
nowhere?
This place is very pivotal. This was the
beginning of the end of the beginning.
This is where I ran away from the
police. How far did we drive to get
here? Took us about half an hour to
drive out here. Over an hour from
Augusta all the way at a dead end road.
And I was sitting down there with my
girlfriend. We were cooking pork chops
over a fire and drinking Joseé Quervo.
And when we went to leave, I remember
she said, "Hey, I want to drive." You
way back here on a little dirt road. She
didn't have a driver's license, but I
really just didn't want to hear. I knew
she would and I was like, "Oh, drive."
Country kids on a dirt road. She's going
kind of fast and I never forget it. That
song Chain Hang Low was playing. I can
still hear it in my ears. Do you chain
Hang Low? And she come around this curve
and I know I'll show it to you when we
go back. And I said, "Hey, there's a
curve. Slow down." And the last thing
she said was, "I'm a race car driver."
That proved out to be false. And she
come and tried to hit the brakes and
fish tailed and lost control. Hit the
embankment. Boom. flipped three times
and landed on the hood. I couldn't even
think. What you car What do you do?
What? Are you okay? Yes, I'm okay. Are
you Yeah, I I didn't have a scratch on.
She had a lump on her head, few
scratches, and you know, nothing
serious. We were both okay. I'll never
forget the last thing that happened when
I put the fire out. We're putting the
fire out and I looked up. I seen two
shooting stars go across the sky. I
thought about that when I we woke up and
we were okay. Okay, first thing, where's
the liquor? So, we take the liquor and
we go and we throw it off in the woods
and it says, "All right, what do we do
now?" No cell service. We walk. We're
going to get the alcohol out of our
bloodstream. And so, we're walking and
it hadn't been real far. And uh we see
headlights. The first person we saw, we
stopped. Hey, we were in a wreck. Can
you give us a lift? Yeah. You want us to
call the cops? No, we already did. Um
they're coming out here. Okay. Well,
take us to our friend's house. Uh Jimmy
and Jane Justice, members of that church
campground. Some of the best humans on
planet Earth. My plan was to drive for a
little while and have them stop and let
us off and then we'd walk the rest of
the way. That's what we were doing.
We're walking in the dark. I ain't got
no shirt on. I ain't got no shoes. And
it was starting to kind of get misty a
little bit. And I remember she was
behind me and she was dragging a bit and
she uh she said, "Hey, I need to stop
and take a rest." Okay. And she sat
down. I remember she kind of sat down
like that, kind of
went and just kind of fell down. And I
was like, you know, you okay? Hey. And
she didn't answer me. And then I know
she wasn't breathing. Got real. I
remembered my YMCA lifeguard training
real quick and I got down there. Come
on. Hey. Hey. Hey, wake up. Wake up. I
was giving her mouth to mouth and she
started breathing. I give her another
breath and she takes two breaths and
then it stops. Oh god. And I pick her up
and I grab her and I run across the
street to the first house I see. Boom.
Boom. Boom. Boom. Boom. Help. Help.
Help. Dude comes the door and I said,
"Hey, hey, we're in a car wreck. My
girlfriend quit breathing." He called
the law immediately and they show up
there rather quickly. They got there,
they're tending to her. There's an
ambulance. There's five cop cars.
There's a fire truck. They Oh, we
already found the car. All this. And I
remember I called my mama on that man's
phone. I said I remember I said, "Mama,
uh, I love you. I'm okay." And I was
talking to her and the man came up and
said, "Hey, you have to come with me.
You got to take a breathalyzer." I said,
"Mama, I love you. I'll call you later."
They took me over there and they asked
me and said, "Who was driving?" And I
see her laying on a gurnie. Mhm. I said
I was driving. To this day, I don't know
why, but with the twists and turns and
the way my life has taken and the things
that I've been through and the I've gone
through and where I am now in life, it
does make sense. Now I know why. I said
I did it because I'm a man and I took
responsibility for letting that woman
drive my vehicle. That's why I did it.
And I felt bad. I felt responsible for
it. So I told him I was driving because
I might as well been. It was my car. It
was my gas. It was my keys. It was my
decision to let her drive. And I said,
"Yeah." And through some misguided
notion of chivalry, I I took that fall.
And they said, "Well, come with me." I
took the breathalyzer and I blew a 0.06.
008's the legal limit. Yeah. And he
said, "Okay." And he put the
breathalyzer down. He said, "Come over
here with me to the car." And he took me
over like this. He was walking me back
like this. And he said, he got real
rough with me. I said, "Whoa, whoa,
whoa." He said, "Come." And he shoved me
up against the car. I said, "What, man?
What?" He goes, "Come on, you you're
going to jail for DUI." I said, "Why?"
You're under 21. Anything over .001 is a
DUI. I was out on bond for that South
Carolina where I had done nothing but
sit on the banks and smoke some weed. I
was out on felony probation in in
Athens, Clark County for pot hashing
mushrooms. I was on misdemeanor
probation for minoring possession up
there the road and I was fitting to go
again. I seen my girlfriend getting put
in the back of aance and his shoved me
up against car for even do man and he
had me up like that against that the car
and he let go with one hand to grab his
handcuffs
gone and it was wet. I took three steps
and boom I slipped and I busted my ass.
Boom. And them cops, there's five cop
cars there. They started laughing and I
got up and I took a step and I slipped
again. And it was wet grass and I was
barefooted. And I remember that one cop
said, "Where you going to go, boy?" I
stood his ass, too. There was a little
pine thicket right down the side uh of
the house. And I took and I hit it and I
shot through it. Now I'm running through
a pine thicket at night. No lights, no
shirt, no shoe. You ever run through a
pine thicket at night? No. You know what
it feels like being hit with a bunch of
sticks? Yeah. I hear them laughing. And
I hear cars starting up and I run and I
get through the edge of that pine thick
and there's a little storm drain and I
literally take and I jump jump out from
behind that pine thick and dive down in
that storm drain like a god bullfrog man
come up and two shot down that way and
then two shot down that way and one hung
back here. I could see his lights
through the woods and I waited and once
that one was gone I got up and I ran
across that road. I was running on the
the yellow line. That way if they get a
canine, they don't know which way I'm
going. Dude, I hadn't been running 15
minutes. I
hear what? How the hell a dog out here?
You want to know what my luck is? The
mother whose door I knocked on, guess
what he does for a living? Raise blood
hounds boy. You can't beat us, Cletus.
God, I'm sprinting. I'm pretty fast. I
ain't see the barbwire fence at the end.
Boom. Straight cut my nipple in half. It
slung me down. Bam. knocked the wind out
of me. And I'm here to tell you, I went
boom boop right back
up, took off running. All I'd had to eat
since lunch was tequila and fried pork
chops. I'm running for my life. I keep
going and at one point I'm about tired,
dude. And I go up and I see this bicycle
leaned up against the house, man. I'm
running. I see it. I get up there. You
never know if somebody going to have a
motion like what. So, I'm easing up
there to it and I'm about to that bike
and all of a sudden I hear a tinking
tink and I look and there's a dog coming
out from under that porch. And a dog
that don't bark is only going to do one
thing. Right. If a dog don't bark, he's
coming to get your ass. And he sure was.
And I
said sprinted gone again as fast as I
could. And
that sprinting for my life. Sprint for
my life. Sprint for my life. gotten
towards I really ran 20 something miles
this night. I'm running down this road
and it finally comes up to this big
intersection, right? And I get there and
my sprint done sprint. I'm done, dog.
I'm tired. And there was some dumpsters
over here, like a real rural trash
station where everybody brings their
household trash. But I literally ran
across that street and I just laid down
in that ditch. I was tired, Cleus. I was
done. I did. And I hadn't been laying
there five minutes. I'm laying there
like
this and I hear a car coming and it
stops. How in the was so pit, dude? But
hey, I was so tired I couldn't have done
nothing. Then I heard the door open and
I kind of looked up there and there's a
Crown Vic sitting there like this. Door
open running and then had got out and is
over there taking a piss on them
dumpsters. Took off and I got up out of
that ditch and I started to run.
Something stopped me. I don't know what
stopped me, you know. I taken this
something said no don't do it. And so I
stopped and I kind of come around the
car like this and I startled the out of
him. Now I probably look like the
Passion of the Christ. I was picking
thorns out of my head for a month after.
For real. I don't know what I look like,
but I didn't have no shirt on, no shoes.
I was cut up from head to toe. And I
come around that corner and said, "Uh,
hey the oh whoa, excuse me. Oh, whoa.
Are you okay?" I said, "Hey, man. I I
had a little flat tire back there. You
think you'd give me a lift in the next
town so I could get some help in the
morning?" And he went, "No." And I was
like, "Oh." He's like, "Sorry, man.
Actually, I can't. This car belongs to
the federal government. My wife can't
even ride in there without written
permission." Really? The federal
government? What do you do for a living,
sir? I'm a food inspector. I work for
the FDA. Oh, okay. That's that's great,
sir. Well, do you think I could use your
cell phone? Mine's dead. I left it in
the car. And yeah, you could. And so, he
hands me a cell phone. It was at that
time I realized I couldn't call my mama.
She wasn't coming. I couldn't call my
daddy. I couldn't call anybody in my
family. There was only one phone number
I remembered. It was a guy. I'm just
going to call him KS. And he answers
after about five rings. And I said,
"Hello, KSKS." He's like, "Who is this?"
I said, "Hey, man, it's Joey." He goes,
"Fels." Yeah. He goes, "What are you
doing? Where are you?" "What?" I said,
"Are the uh concentration me, can you
come get me?" He said, "What?" I said,
"I'll explain later. The concentration,
can you can come get me?" He goes,
"What? Where are you? I'm standing under
a billboard with a parrot on it for
Malibu Rum. He goes, "Are there some
little dumpsters off on the other side?"
I said, "Yeah." He goes, "At a little
intersection?" I said, "Yeah." He goes,
"I know exactly where you are." And my
dear friend KS came and got me. And
that's how my 20 months as a fugitive
began. And that's why we're here today,
Jesse.